Jennifer Collins

5011 SE Kelly St Portland OR 97206

(503) 208-4341 JnnfrCllns@gmail.com

Administrative Assistant

Driven and detail-oriented administrative assistant with over five years experience performing a wide variety of general and specialized office duties in several industries and environments who has proven capable of providing excellent administrative support. Possess excellent communication skills, project and time management ability, as well as the ability to quickly learn, adapt and apply new skills in a proficient manner.

Professional and Technical Skills

- Proficient with Mac, Microsoft and Linux
- · Proficient with Microsoft Office, Adobe Office Suite, Raiser's Edge, iShip,
- Extensive experience with HTML, CSS, Social Media, and Internet Research
- Customer Service
- Project management
- Multi-Line phone system
- Light billing and book keeping
- Database entry and management
- Travel and event coordination
- · Fundraising and grantwriting
- Calendar management and scheduling
- Preparation and review of business correspondence
- Basic French language skills

Education

Portland State University 2012

Toulan School of Urban Studies Community Development B.A.

Relevant Experience

Community Outreach Coordinator

Bike Farm, Portland OR August 2007-March 2009

- Coordinated outreach and fundraising events including auctions, dances, tabling events and neighborhood block parties
- Coordinated bicycle maintenance workshops
- Played a key role in obtaining a level of funding and sponsorship to move Bike Farm to a commercially zoned location
- Recruited and coordinated volunteers
- Created promotional materials using Adobe Creative Suite
- Social Media promotion through Facebook, Flickr and blogging

Family Services Assistant

Habitat for Humanity, Portland OR September 2007-June 2008

- Coordinated orientations and workshops for volunteers and potential homeowners
- · Responded to a high volume of program information inquiries
- Database management using Excel and Raiser's Edge
- Tabled at homeownership fairs
- Worked with other housing organizations in the Portland Metro area to find potential homeowner program applicants
- Assisted current homeowners with concerns
- Entered application data and organized financial files for over 200 potential homeowners

Records Management Assistant

Bureau of Development, City of Portland, Portland OR January 2008-July 2008

- Database Management for multiple programs, including Living smart Houses and the Portland Renewable Fuel Standard
- Responded to inquiries about BDS's programs from city governments worldwide
- Wrote short articles for BDS's public blog and departmental newsletter
- Scanned and cataloged hundreds of geotechnical documents for digital archival

Customer Service Associate

UPS Store, Portland OR September 2005-September 2007 and June 2010-June 2011

- Shipping domestically and internationally via UPS, FedEx, USPS, DHL, and freight companies
- Expert packing of a wide range of items for safe shipping, including large, high value, and unusually sized items
- Copy and Printing services
- · Graphic design
- Cash management
- Opening and closing keyholder
- Inventory and purchasing of printing, shipping and office supplies
- Data entry and Management
- Sorting a high volume of mail for mailbox customers
- File Organization and Management

Customer Service Associate/Framer

Deck the Walls, Yorktown Heights NY January 1998-January 2002

- Display design
- Sales and assembly of custom framing
- Cash Management
- Opening and closing keyholder